Guide to the Yehuda Amichai Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Yehuda Amichai, 1952-1999; Series II; 8.97; (22 boxes)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - "Al kevurah shel Aleks Blokh," draft, holograph, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 1218)
    - "Al Yofi," notes, holograph, television program, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 1219)
    - ["ha-Havatat ha-roman"?], draft, holograph, corrected (Box 35, Folder 1220)
    - ["Hu ahav otah..."], draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1221)
    - ["I am tired of giving birth..."], [excerpt?], computer printout, 1994 May (Box 35, Folder 1222)
    - [Ich bin einmal nach..."], autobiographical statement, printed version, 1992 Jan (Box 35, Folder 1223)
    - Memoir on Charlie Shlush, draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1224)
    - "Nevi anshav," draft, holograph, corrected, 1988 Nov 24 (Box 35, Folder 1225)
    - ["Please find enclosed..."], open letter, typescript mimeograph, 1974 Jun 5 (Box 35, Folder 1226)
    - "Prose," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1227)
    - ["Reading this book.."], blurb, computer printout, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1228)
    - Selections, computer printout, photocopy, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1229)
    - "Shirey ha-milhamah shel Shemuel ha-Nagid," by Ch. Shirman, in hand of Yehuda Amichai, 1952-1953 (Box 35, Folder 1230)
    - "Words for Michael Mooij," draft, holograph, 1994 Jul (Box 35, Folder 1231)
    - "Yehuda Amichai," autobiographical statement, draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1232)
    - Untitled notes and drafts (Box 35, Folder 1233-1235)
    - Untitled notes and drafts (Box 36, Folder 1236-1239)
- Writings of Others, 1962-1998; Series III; 1.68; (4 boxes)
  Series III, Writings of Others, is first arranged alphabetically by last name and then by title.
  - Abadi, Adina
    - "Bererah makhlilah u-vererah motsiah bi-leshon hakhamenu zikhronam li-verakhah," printed version, 1964-1965 (Box 37, Folder 1240)
  - Abramson, Glenda
    - "The Distant Self: Aspects of Alienation in Contemporary Hebrew Poetry," lecture, printed version, 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 1241)
  - Alter, Robert
    - "Beauty and the Best," review, printed version, The New Republic, photocopy, 1994 Oct 10 (Box 37, Folder 1242)
    - "Confronting the Holocaust: Three Israeli Novels," article, printed version, Commentary, 1966 Mar (Box 37, Folder 1243)
    - "Israeli Writers & Their Problems," article, printed version, Commentary, 1962 Jul (Box 37, Folder 1244)
    - "Mishak ve-hazon be-shirato shel Yehuda Amihai," lecture, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 1245)
    - "Nabokov's Ardor," article, printed version, Commentary, photocopy, 1969 Aug (Box 37, Folder 1246)
    - "On Lea Goldberg & S.Y. Agnon," article, printed version, Commentary, 1970 May (Box 37, Folder 1247)
    - "Poetry in Israel," article, printed version, Commentary, 1966 Mar (Box 37, Folder 1248)
    - "A Portrait of Yehuda Amichai (1986)," book chapter, printed version, Hebrew and Modernity, photocopy, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 1249)
    - "Tyrants and Butterflies," review, printed version, The New Republic, photocopy, 1990 Oct 15 (Box 37, Folder 1250)
    - "Varieties of Jewish Verse," article, printed version, Commentary, photocopy, 1981 Jul (Box 37, Folder 1251)
    - "Vistas of Annihilation," article, printed version, Commentary, photocopy, 1985 Jan (Box 37, Folder 1252)
    - Untitled page from article, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1253)
  - Arpaly, Boaz
    - "Al ha-mashmaut ha-politit shel shirat Amihai," essay, computer printout, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1254)
    - "ha-Anakat toar doktor le-shem kavod le-meshorer Yehuda Amihai," computer printout, 1995 Feb 18 (Box 37, Folder 1255)
    - "Milim she-lo mi-kan ve-lo me-akhshav'," essay, printed version, 1979 Dec (Box 37, Folder 1256)
  - Atchity, Kenneth John
    - "Poetics," review, printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1257)
  - Avinor, Gitah
    - "Omanut o manerizm," article, printed version, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1258)
  - Bachmann, Ingeborg
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1259)
  - Bao, Zhongguo Wenhua
    - "The Famous Israeli Poet Yehuda Amichai," article, computer printout, n.y. Jul 21 (Box 37, Folder 1260)
  - Baranow, Joan
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1261)
  - Bargad, Warren
    - "Children and Lovers: On Yehuda Amichai's Poetic Works," article, printed version, Midstream, 1975 Oct (Box 37, Folder 1262)
  - Bartini, K. A.
    - "Israel," poem, printed version, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 1263)
  - Bartsch, Monika
    - "Fiktion und Wirklichkeit in Bezug auf Würzburg..." essay, computer printout, 1994 Feb 2 (Box 37, Folder 1264)
      Includes photograph of Amichai
  - Basbane, Nicholas A.
    - A Gentle Madness, book excerpt, printed version, photocopy, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 1265)
  - Basse, Michael
    - ["Ich habe Deutschland..."], radio address, 1998 Mar 5 (Box 37, Folder 1266)
  - Beichman, Janine
    - "Amichai in Tokyo Feb 93," poem, fax, 1993 Feb 26 (Box 37, Folder 1267)
  - Besiso, Moayin
    - "Ketsef ha-sabon," excerpt, typescript, corrected, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 1268)
  - Bloch, Chana
    - "Between Cultures, or, a Jew at the Opera," essay, computer printout, 1998 Feb (Box 37, Folder 1269)
    - "The Politics of Translation: Amichai and Ravikovitch in English," article, printed version, Tikkun, photocopy, 1989 Jul (Box 37, Folder 1270)
  - Blumenthal, Michael
    - "It is Best Not to Sit at Your Desk..." poem, computer printout, 1986 Nov 12 (Box 37, Folder 1271)
  - Bohmeier, Ute
    - "Trauer und Trauma: Jehuda Amichai- Aharon Appelfeld," essay, typescript, photocopy, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 1272)
  - Breslin, Paul
    - Untitled article (incomplete), printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1273)
  - Brodsky, Louis Daniel
    - Gestapo Crows: Holocaust Poems, draft, title page, 1992 Jan 8 (Box 37, Folder 1274)
  - Bronner, Leila Leah
    - "Israel Through Poetry and Prose (1948-1972)," lecture, printed version, 1972 Oct 15 (Box 37, Folder 1275)
  - Cohen, Joseph
    - Voices of Israel, draft, [computer printout?] and printed publicity, 1987-1990 (Box 37, Folder 1276)
  - Cooperman, Stanley
    - "Arrival and Departure," poem, draft, typescript, 1973 Jan (Box 37, Folder 1277)
  - [Cutter, William?]
    - "Why Amichai," article, draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1278)
  - Dalit, Ron
    - "Ha-ishah bi-yetsirat Yehuda Amihai," thesis, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 1279)
  - Datan, Nancy
    - "Yehuda Amichai: A Devotee Dissents," open letter, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1280)
  - Dewey, Donald
    - "The Idealist," poem, draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1281)
  - Dunning, Stephen
    - "Leaves," poem, typescript and printed versions, Michigan Quarterly Review, photocopy (Box 37, Folder 1282)
  - Eckhard Elial, Michel
    - Introduction to Poèmes, printed version, photocopy, [1985?] (Box 37, Folder 1283)
  - Elitzor, Shulmit
    - "Shirim hadashim le-Rav Shemuel ha-Nagid," offprint, Tarbits, [1989-1990] (Box 37, Folder 1284)
  - Ezrahi, Sidra DeKoven
    - "Our Homeland, the Text..." article, printed version, Michigan Quarterly Review, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 1285)
  - Feldman, Ziva
    - "Yehuda Amihai: Matakim kinetiyim mi-tsurah le-mashmaut," dissertation, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 1286)
  - Felstiner, [John?]
    - Untitled fragment, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1287)
  - Fisch, Harold
    - "The Absent God," article, printed version, Judaism, photocopy, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 1288)
  - Fishelov, David
    - "Yehuda Amichai: A Modern Metaphysical Poet," article, printed version, Orbis Litterarum, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 1289)
  - Flade, Rolande
    - Dissertation synopsis, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1290)
  - Flinker, ----
    - "Angelic Sex Past and Present..." essay, draft, typescript carbon (Box 38, Folder 1291)
  - Freistadt, Becky
    - "A Letter to Palestinian Writers and Intellectuals in the Granada Conference," open letter, computer printout, 1993 Dec (Box 38, Folder 1292)
  - [Fu, Hao?]
    - ["I am greatly honoured..."], address, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1293)
    - "Yehuda Amichai and his Poems," article, table of contents, printed version, Foreign Literatures, photocopy, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 1294)
  - Gertler, Pesha
    - "On Meeting Yehuda Amichai," poem, draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1295)
  - Gilbert, Martin
    - "Celebration in Jerusalem," [open letter?], typescript, photocopy, 1990 Jan 16 (Box 38, Folder 1296)
  - Rabbi Gliksberg
    - No title, speech, computer printout, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1297)
  - Grossman, Anita Susan
    - "The Lover as Poet: Yehuda Amichai," review, printed version, Jewish Book News, photocopy, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1298)
  - Halkin, Hillel
    - "Yehuda Amichai: The Poet as Prose Writer," address, printed version, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1299)
  - Harris, Judith
    - "Letter to Ama[i]chai Long Overdue," poem, draft, typescript, 1980 Nov (Box 38, Folder 1300)
  - Hegorni-Green, A.
    - "ha-Meshorer medaber al shirato," article, printed version, Kavim le-horaat ha-shirah ha-hadashah, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1301)
  - Hellmann, Norbert
    - "Jewish Life in Würzburg (pre World War II)," article, printed version, Mitteilungen, photocopy, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1302)
  - Herbert, Zbigniew
    - "Do Yehudy Amichaja," poem, printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1303)
      Includes Hebrew translation by Gabriel Moked
  - Hessing, Jakob
    - "Reise in den Spiegelsaal: Jehuda Amichais deutsch-judisches Dilemma," review, computer printout, [1992?] (Box 38, Folder 1304)
  - Hillman, Brenda
    - "Readings & Interviews with Contemporary Poets," article, printed version, American Poetry Archives News, photocopy, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1305)
  - Hirsch, Edward
    - "Poet at the Window," review, printed version, The American Poetry Review, photocopy, 1981 May (Box 38, Folder 1306)
  - [Homnick, Yaakov I.?]
    - "Emunah," poem, holograph, 1967 Jan 17 (Box 38, Folder 1307)
  - Hoopes, Lynn Ray
    - "Alpha Centauri," poem, computer printout, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1308)
  - Hughes, Ted
    - "Hakdamah me-et Ted Yuz," forward, computer printout, 1993 oct 17 (Box 38, Folder 1309)
    - [ Shual ha-mahashavah ?], galley proof, photocopy, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 1310-1311)
    - "Yehuda Amichai: Il dramma di Israele," article, printed version, Italian translation (2 copies), n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1312)
  - Intrator, Roseline
    - " Great Tranquility: Questions and Answers ," review, printed version, Magill's Literary Annual, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 1313)
    - "Yehuda Amichai and the Interrelatedness of all Things," review, printed version (Box 38, Folder 1314)
  - Irwin, Mark
    - "Toward a Tragic Wisdom and Beyond," review, printed version, Kenyon Review, photocopy (Box 38, Folder 1315)
  - Jaffe, Dan
    - "They Would Be My Poems," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1316)
  - Jelen, Sheila Elana
    - "Hillel Panel - Lake Tahoe," address, computer printout, corrected, 1992 Jul 29 (Box 38, Folder 1317)
  - Jong, Erica
    - [Poems], printed versions and typescript carbon, 1987-1991, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1318)
  - Kempe, Cordula
    - "Deutsch-Jüdische Portraits," book proposal, computer printout, 1994 Apr (Box 38, Folder 1319)
  - Kincaid, Michael
    - " Great Tranquility: Questions and Answers ," review, typescript, photocopy, 1984 Aug 16 (Box 38, Folder 1320)
  - Kirschen, Yehudit
    - "Jerusalem Poet Yehuda Amichai: Reflections on Love, War and Tradition," article, printed version (Box 38, Folder 1321)
      Includes Spanish translation
  - Kohse, Petra
    - Nicht von Jetzt, nicht von Hier, review, typescript, photocopy, 1992 Oct 30 (Box 38, Folder 1322)
  - Komem, [Aharon?]
    - "Pegishah," poem, printed version, photocopy, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 1323)
  - Kovner, Abba
    - "Nearby Music," poem, printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1324)
  - Kramer, Shalom
    - "Hemshekh ve-hidush be-shirat Yehudah Amihai," article, printed version, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1325)
  - Kranich, Stefanie
    - "Verarbeitung der Geschehnisse im Dritten Reich in der Literatur," essay, computer printout, 1994 Apr 20 (Box 38, Folder 1326)
      Includes letter from Kranish to Amichai
  - Krauze, Enrique
    - "Encuentros con Israel," essay, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1327)
  - Kronfeld, Chana
    - "Allusion: An Israeli Perspective," article, printed version, Prooftexts, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 1328)
    - "The Wisdom of Camouflage: Between Rhetoric and Philosophy in Amichai's Poetic System," article, draft, computer printout, corrected, and printed version, Prooftexts, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 1329)
  - Laor, Dan
    - "The Vehicle of Parody," essay, offprint, The Jerusalem Quarterly, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 1330)
  - Leontief, Estelle
    - "Starting Over," poem, printed version, [ Jewish Frontier ?], n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1331)
  - Levin, Zel
    - " Voices of Israel ," review, computer printout, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1332)
  - Levine, Herbert J.
    - "How Jewish are Israel's Poets?" article, printed version, Jewish Spectator, photocopy (2 copies), 1984 (Box 38, Folder 1333)
  - Levitsky, Ruth
    - "The Radio Drama of Yehuda Amichai," thesis, computer printout, 1997 Oct (Box 38, Folder 1334)
  - Loschütz, Gert
    - "Über den israelischen Dichter Jehuda Amichai," radio broadcast, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1992 Feb 18 (Box 39, Folder 1335)
  - Mazor, Yair
    - "Farewell to Arms and Sentimentality," article, reprint, World Literature Today, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 1336)
    - "Meuhar be-hai ani ba," essay, photocopy, printed version, Moznayim, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 1337)
  - McKnight, Christina S.
    - "Lars Forssell: The Jester as Conscience," article, reprint, World Literature Today, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 1338)
  - Meckel, Christoph
    - "Sätze für Jehuda Amichai," article, printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1339)
  - Motzkin, Elizabeth Fullon
    - "Yehuda Amichai's Yom Kippur: How Politics and Poetry Mix," article, typescript, photocopy, 1979 Nov 4 (Box 39, Folder 1340)
  - Müller, Karlheinz
    - "Zeitlosigkeit Anmerkungen zu einem Gedicht von Jehuda Amichaj," article, computer printout, corrected, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1341)
  - Nogah, Rivkah
    - "Negudiot be-shiro shel Yehuda Amihai," essay, typescript, 1968 Sep (Box 39, Folder 1342)
  - Ozick, Cynthia
    - "Tribute to Yehuda Amichai," address, typescript, 1983 May 16 (Box 39, Folder 1343)
  - Pagel, Gerda
    - "Warten auf den Poeten," essay, draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, and printed version, photocopy, 1985 Apr (Box 39, Folder 1344)
  - Piper, Ernst
    - "Meine Autoren," essay, printed version, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 1345)
  - Raab, Larry
    - "Love Poem," typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1346)
  - Ramras-Rauch, Gila
    - "Israel," review, printed version, World Literature Today, photocopy, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 1347)
    - "Modern Hebrew Verse," article, reprint, World Literature Today, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 1348)
  - Rivlin, Aher
    - [Poems], typescript carbon and typescript, photocopy (Box 39, Folder 1349)
  - Rodner, Tamar
    - "Ben H. N. Byalik li-Yehudah Amihai," excerpt, printed version, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1350)
  - Rosenthal, M. L.
    - "Israel of the Poets," article, printed version, The Nation (2 copies), 1970 Dec 14 (Box 39, Folder 1351)
  - Rotchin, Glen
    - "Dinner with Amichai (27/09/89)," poem, computer printout, [1989?] (Box 39, Folder 1352)
  - Rozen, Tovah
    - "'Kemo be-shir shel Shemuel ha- Nagid: ben Shemuel ha-Nagid vi-Yehudah Amihai," offprint, [1994-1995] (Box 39, Folder 1353)
  - Rudman, Mark
    - "Car, Bomb, God," review, galley proof, corrected and annotated, and printed version, The Nation, photocopy, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 1354)
  - Russell, James R.
    - "The Book of Six Thousand: An Armenian Magical Text," essay, reprint, Bazmavep, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 1355)
  - Ryder, Sarah
    - "To Yehuda Amichai After a Trip..." poem, draft, typescript, 1983 Dec 10 (Box 39, Folder 1356)
  - Sachs, Arieh
    - "The Poetry of Yehuda Amichai," article, reprint, Judaism, 1965 (Box 39, Folder 1357)
  - Sager, Adam
    - "To You," poem, draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1358)
  - Sandler, Luada
    - [Poems], drafts, typescript, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1359)
  - Schimmel, Harold
    - "An Informal Note," review, draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1360)
  - Schulman, Grace
    - "In My Time, In My Place," review, printed version, The Nation, photocopy, 1982 May 29 (Box 39, Folder 1361)
  - Schultz, Philip
    - My Guardian Angel Stein, chapbook (2 copies), 1986 (Box 39, Folder 1362)
    - "Stein, Goodbye," poem, draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1985 Apr 21 (Box 39, Folder 1363)
  - Schwarcz, Vera
    - "A Dream After Hearing Amichai on the First..." poem, computer printout, [1984 Feb?] (Box 39, Folder 1364)
    - "Yehuda Amichai," address, printed version, Hamakkor, 1993 Feb (Box 39, Folder 1365)
  - Schwartz, Howard
    - " Amen ," review, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1366)
    - "Amichai Dreams," notes, typescript, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1367)
    - "Our Angels," poem, printed version, 1975 Aug 8 (Box 39, Folder 1368)
  - Seraf-Golad, Nili
    - "Veha-nedarim lo nedarim," essay, computer printout, photocopy, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1369)
  - Sereni, Vittorio
    - [Poems], English translations, typescript, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1370)
  - Shamyar, Meir
    - "Megamot ba-mishpat," article, printed version, Iyune Mishpat, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 1371)
  - Shiloni, Ben-Ami
    - Hashkafot Yapaniyot al Yehudim ve-Yahadut, printed version, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 1372)
  - Shiraf-Golad, Nili
    - ""Ve-ha-nedarim lo nedarim" Yehuda Amihai: Gam ha-egrof hayah paam yad petuha ve-etsbaot," printed version, Siman Kria, photocopy, 1991 Jul 22 (Box 39, Folder 1373)
  - Shiryon, Sandra Levine
    - "Half a Hope: Songs of the Land of Zion, Jerusalem of Yehuda Amichai," thesis, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 1374)
  - Shoren (Singer), Doctor Shlomo
    - "Shorashim ve-khishufam al ha-zikah ben ha-arkheologyah veha-psikhoanalizah," essay, printed version, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1375)
  - Shmueli, A.
    - "Tazkir," typescript, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1376)
  - Silberschlag, Eisig
    - "Redemptive Vision in Hebrew Literature," article, printed version, World Literature Today, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1377)
  - Simkin, Ariel
    - "Structual Analysis of the Human Foot in Standing Posture" (incomplete), thesis, photocopy, 1982 Aug (Box 39, Folder 1378)
  - Sommers, Fred
    - "Why is There Something and Not Nothing?" article, printed version, Analysis, 1966 Jun (Box 39, Folder 1379)
  - Sontag, Susan
    - "The Letter Scene," article, printed version, The New Yorker, photocopy, 1986 Aug 18 (Box 39, Folder 1380)
  - Stardelov, Georgi
    - "On the Poetry of Yehuda Amichai," speech, English translation, computer printout (3 copies), [1995] (Box 39, Folder 1381)
  - Steidle, Hans
    - "L. Frank: Die Jünger Jesu: Zur Revision eines verkannten Exilromans," printed version, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 1382)
    - "Projekte zur Würzburger Stadtgeschichte," compilation, photocopy, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 1383)
    - "Zum Motiv der gerechten Rache bei Leonhard Frank und Jehuda Amichai," essay, printed version, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 1384)
  - Sternberg, Janet
    - Phantom Limb, title page, computer printout, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 1385)
    - The Writer and Her Work, printed publicity, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 1386)
  - Stiller, Nikki
    - "In the Great Wilderness," review, printed version, Parnassus, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 1387)
  - Swados, Elizabeth
    - "Acknowledgements," printed version, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1388)
  - Sweet, Frederick
    - "Yehuda Amichai: A Film Portrait," film treatment, typescript, [ca. 1974] (Box 40, Folder 1389)
  - Tal, Eliyahu
    - Whose Jerusalem (incomplete), computer printout, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 1390)
      Includes letter and note
  - Talmide Ort Ako
    - "... Be-alfe yetsiot zehirot-- yerukot..." computer printout, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 1391)
  - [Tarnoc?], John
    - "A Poem for Yehuda Amichai," poem, typescript, photocopy, 1993 Jan (Box 40, Folder 1392)
  - Tate, Allen
    - "The Translation of Poetry," lecture, printed version, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 1393)
  - Temkin, Mordecai
    - "Put on Your Festive Robes, Jerusalem," poem, Hebrew and English translation, computer printout, 1993 Sep 28 (Box 40, Folder 1394)
  - Thumboo, Edwin
    - [Poems], [typescript photocopy?], n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1395)
  - Tzvik, Yehudit
    - "Ba-derekh el ha-shalvah ha- gedolah," article, printed version, Moznayim, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 1396)
  - Xu, Xin
    - "A General Introduction to Contemporary Hebrew Literature," article, Foreign Literature Review, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 1397)
  - Vallotton, Jena-Pierre
    - [Poems], computer printouts, [1992?] (Box 40, Folder 1398)
  - Wallmann, Jürgen Peter
    - "Der israelische Lyriker Jehuda Amichai aus Würzburg," article, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1994 Aug 5 (Box 40, Folder 1399)
    - "Jehuda Amichai: Der Dichter an der Schwelle zum dritten Jahrtausend," printed version (5 copies) (Box 40, Folder 1400)
    - "Die Verwandlungen der Welt: Westfälische Literatur -- gibt's die?" article, printed version, Westfalen-Spiegel, photocopy, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 1401)
  - Waysman, Dvora
    - "Israeli Poet at the Window: Yehuda Amichai," article, typescript, 1981 May 10 (Box 40, Folder 1402)
  - Weinfeld, David
    - "Lo keva-rosh ela ke-deshe: mivneh ve-retorikah be-dimui ha-poeti," article, offprint, [1992-1993] (Box 40, Folder 1403)
  - Weiss, S.
    - "Tsiyon yom Yerushalayim," speech, computer printout, 1995 May 29 (Box 40, Folder 1404)
  - Whitman, Ruth
    - "Motor Car, Bomb, God: Israeli Poetry in Translation," article, printed version, The Massachusetts Review, photocopy, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 1405)
  - Whitson, Carter H.
    - "Choosing: Belongingness and Love Needs..." article, typescript, photocopy, 1975 Jul 25 (Box 40, Folder 1406)
  - Wiggermann, Karl-Friedrich
    - "Pratiscke Theologie und Heileges Land," article, printed version, photocopy, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 1407)
  - Wiltmann, Ingrid
    - "Jehuda Amichai," poem, typescript, photocopy, 1998 Jun 5 (Box 40, Folder 1408)
      Includes note from Amichai to "Ingrid"
  - Wollach, Yona
    - [Poems], printed versions, photocopies, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1409)
  - Wu, Ji-Mei
    - "Hardship and Ideal," holograph and computer printout, 1993 Apr 28 (Box 40, Folder 1410)
  - Yelin, Shulamis
    - "The Amichai Poems," computer printouts, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1411)
  - Zach, Nathan
    - [Poems], printed versions, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1412)
  - Zandabank, Shimon
    - "ha-Gaaguim el ha-pahot," article, printed version, photocopy, Sefarim, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1413)
  - Zeldah
    - [Poems], printed versions, photocopies, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1414)
  - Zivah, ----
    - "Shirim shel malah ve-shirim shel matah," poems, printed version, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1415)
  - Unidentified school
    - Student writings, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1416)
  - Unidentified
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1978-1997, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1417-1419)
    - [Empty folder] (Box 40, Folder 1420)
  - Translations
    - Miscellaneous, typescript mimeograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1421)
      Includes translations of poems by Rafael Alberti, Homero Aridjis, Ivan Drach, Alfonso Gatto, Allen Ginsberg, José Pacheco, Octavio Paz and Vittorio Sereni
- Journals, 1954-1998; Series IV; 3.09; (8 boxes)
  Series IV, Journals, is arranged chronologically.
  - Journals, 1954-1957 (Box 41, Folder 1422-1429)
  - Journals, 1957-1958 (Box 41, Folder 1430-1437)
  - Journals, 1958 (Box 41, Folder 1438-1445)
  - Journals, 1958 (Box 41, Folder 1446)
  - Journals, 1958-1959 (Box 42, Folder 1447-1454)
  - Journals, 1959-1960 (Box 42, Folder 1455-1462)
  - Journals, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 1463-1470)